Sodaba Ahmadi

Full Stack Engineer (React, NodeJS) with **1 year and 7 months** of experience. Strong ownership mindset, proficient in backend and frontend technologies, excellent communication and collaboration skills, and a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Privately at home

Java, Unity Teacher

USA. California (Remote)

Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

- Taught Unity game platform and Java.
- Built relationships with students and ensured all students felt attended to with personalized feedback, class discussions, and encouragement.
- Designed and implemented performance improvement plans for underperforming students in consultation with parents.
- Methodically planned and executed on lesson plans, including collecting necessary resources to complete a given lessons.

Herat University

Assistant Teacher

Afghanistan, Herat

Jun 2020 - May 2021

- Assisted in Teaching HCI (Human Computer interaction) and Enterprise Softwires subject.
- Assisted in answering students' questions, enabling the teacher to complete 90% of lessons plans on time.
- Created individual homework assignments for students based on their progress in specific sections of the curriculum.
- Established healthy relationships with students by actively supporting students with academic and behavioral aid.
- Reinforced students learning skills and materials through daily and weekly check-ins, informal assessments, and observations.
- Partnered with teachers to implement developmentally suitable lessons tailored for students.
- Provided timely and frequent feedback to students, fostering an environment of open communication and interest in discovery.
- Collaborated with 2 teachers to prepare instructional materials and classroom displays for 2 classes.
- Maintained administrative records and prepared required reports for 2 classes and 120 students.

Digital To Future

Full Stack Engineer

USA, California (Remote)

Jan 2019 - Jul 2020

- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Identify and resolve web development issues reported by clients and completed different debugs.
- Design and implemented new product features.
- Identify opportunities to improve efficiency and functionality for servers, databases, and Application Programming Interface (APIs).
- Collaborated with other developers and stakeholders to create and maintain unit tests for website codes, resulting in a 10% reduction in bug-related delays and an overall improvement in code quality.

Sodabaahmadig6106@gmail.com +93794756445 https://www.linkedin.com/in/sod aba-ahmadi-324835197 https://github.com/SodabaAhma di

TECHNOLOGIES

Proficient

NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, Reactjs, Vuejs, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign,

Familiar

Spring Boot, Python, MongoDB, RESTful API, AWS, Microsoft Suite, Adobe Premiere, Adobe Aftereffect

LANGUAGES

English C1, fluent Persian native Pashto C1, fluent

EDUCATION

Herat University. Degree in Software Engineering Afghanistan, Herat 2018 – 2021

Certificates

CODETOINSPIRE, learning UX/UI design Afghanistan, Herat Currently

CODETOINSPIRE, Certificate in Graphic Design **Afghanistan**, **Herat** 2023

CODETOINSPIRE, Certificate in Unity Development Afghanistan, Herat 2019 – 2021

Herat university courses, Certificate in web design Afghanistan, Herat 2018

Herat university courses, Certificate in JavaFX Afghanistan, Herat 2018

ICT department of Herat Education Directorate, Certificate in ICDL Afghanistan, Herat 2014

PROJECTS

Social media (currently). Full Stack Developer, react and nodejs, Web Site

taskmate (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site URL: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/taskmate-firstproject

cinemate (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site

URL: https://qithub.com/SodabaAhmadi/cinemate-secondproject

tour and travel (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site

URL: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/Tour-and-Travel-thirdproject

codebook (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site **URL**: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/codebook

shopmate (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site **URL**: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/shopmate

shopmate (2023). Full Stack Developer, react and redux, Web Site **URL:** https://qithub.com/SodabaAhmadi/shopmate-redux

wordcount (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site URL: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/wordcount

writenode (2023). Full Stack Developer, react, Web Site URL: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/writenode

ESMO FAMIL (2020- 2021). Developer, Unity Engine and C#, Android Game

Online Shop (2021). Full Stack Developer, Vuejs and Spring Boot, Web Site

URL: https://github.com/SodabaAhmadi/project-online-shop